<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Portfolio Website for Elia Waidele</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Portfolio Website for Elia Waidele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change and Temperature Anomalies</title>
      <link>/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>For our study of climate change and temperature anomalies we can find data on the Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies in the Northern Hemisphere at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies.
We use the following code to load our data.
weather &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;https://data.giss.nasa.gov/gistemp/tabledata_v3/NH.Ts+dSST.csv&amp;quot;, skip = 1, na = &amp;quot;***&amp;quot;)skim(weather)Table 1: Data summaryNameweatherNumber of rows140Number of columns19_______________________Column type frequency:numeric19________________________Group variablesNoneVariable type: numeric</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Steven Spielberg beat Tim Burton in IMDB ratings?</title>
      <link>/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>IMDB Internet Movie Database is an online database of information related to films, television programs, home videos, video games, and streaming content – including cast, production crew and personal biographies, plot summaries, trivia, ratings, and fan and critical reviews.
Originally a fan-operated website, the database is today owned and operated by IMDB.com, Inc., a subsidiary of Amazon.
As of January 2020, IMDB has approximately 6.5 million titles (including episodes) and 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returns of Financial Stocks</title>
      <link>/projects/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project3/</guid>
      <description>In the following we perform analyses on Returns of a select number of Financial Stocks utilizing the monthly, yearly and daily returns to gauge behavior of these stocks over a fixed period of time. We obtain our data from the nyse.csv dataset which contains 508 stocks listed on the NYSE, their ticker symbol, name, the IPO year, and the sector and industry the company operates in.
First of all we have to load our data set:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Do People Drink The Most Beer, Wine And Spirits?</title>
      <link>/projects/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project4/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2014, fivethiryeight.com published an article on alcohol consumption in different countries. We load The data drinks as part of the fivethirtyeight package.
library(fivethirtyeight)data(drinks)First of all we take a look at our data set via glimpse and skimr::skim to get a better understanding of our data, the variable types included in the data set and the occurance of missing values.
glimpse(drinks)## Rows: 193## Columns: 5## $ country &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Afghanistan&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Albania&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Algeria&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
